<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Souvik Haldar</title>
    <link>https://www.souvikhaldar.info/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Souvik Haldar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 20:57:31 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.souvikhaldar.info/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Farewell to the first workplace of my life</title>
      <link>https://www.souvikhaldar.info/articles/farewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 20:57:31 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.souvikhaldar.info/articles/farewell/</guid>
      <description>30th of April marked my last working day at Kartbites, where I landed after getting the first job of my life as Software Engineer (Backend).
Sometime around August of 2017, I was pretty sad one night, because campus placements were going on but I was not able to sit for most of the interviews because of low grades. Also, that particular day there was a recruitment drive for a role which I felt I could do very well because I had just done internship in the same domain at hasura but alas, my grades didn&amp;rsquo;t meet the requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The good and bad of asking for help</title>
      <link>https://www.souvikhaldar.info/articles/help/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 13:02:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.souvikhaldar.info/articles/help/</guid>
      <description>We all have our vulnerabilities, the way we deal with them varies. To me (and maybe to many more) asking for help seems the best way, because by doing that you start to express the problem in the best way possible so as to make the person understand. In trying to do that we do a very major thing, that is, we formulate the problem statement. Most of the times we don&amp;rsquo;t know what the problem is, hence doing this makes us understand the problem in a better way, we start getting a clear picture.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>